David E. Lilienthal Papers, 1900-1981 (bulk 1950-1981 ): Inventory MC148
EADs for public policy collection from import batch
- Series 3: Correspondence and Related Materials, 1912-1949; 105 boxes; 2 items
  - Subseries 3I: 1948, 1944-1948; 8 boxes
    - Kirschten, Ernest, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Knowland, William, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Ladies Home Journal, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - La Follette, Philip F, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Lasker, Albert D, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Leahy, William D, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Lederer, A.M., 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Life Magazine, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Lilienthal, Alfred M, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Link, Henry C, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Lloyd, L. Duncan, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Long, Perrin H, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Longden, Henry B, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Lubell, Samuel, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Lucas, Jim G, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Luckman, Charles, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - McCormack, John W, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - McCormick, Robert, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - McDonnell, R.E., 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - McMahon, Brien, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - MacLeish, Archibald: "A Progress Report on Atomic Energy, A Dialogue with ... David E. Lilienthal Life Magazine, 1948 September 2; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Mahon, George, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Mallinckrodt Chemical Works, St. Louis, Missouri, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Markel, Lester, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Marks, Herbert S, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Marshall, George C, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Marton, Andrew, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Merriam, Charles E, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Meyer, Eugene, 1948; 1 box (Box 133)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Monroney, Mike, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Morgan, Harcourt A, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Murphy, Walter J, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Murrow, Edward R, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Muste, W, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Myers, Francis J, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Myler, Joseph, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - National Democratic Finance Committee, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Neylan, John Francis, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - New York Times, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Newton, Emmett Stanford, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Nicely, James Mount, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Norris, Tennessee: Sale of Properties, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - O'Brien, John Lord, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Ohio Farm Bureau Federation, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Owen, Kenneth W, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Oxnam, Bishop G. Bromley, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Patterson, Robert P, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Patton, James G, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Pettes, C. Rockwell, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Phillips, John, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Pike, Sumner T, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Pimlott, A.R., 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Pinkus, H.L., 1944-1948; 1 box
      - Re Publications by David E. Lilienthal, 1944-1948; 1 box
        - Senior Scholastic. "Atomic Energy ... And You,", 1948 April 12; 1 box (Box 134)
        - New York Times Magazine. "U.P.S. - Universal Public Service,", 1948 June 27; 1 box (Box 134)
        - Survival or Suicide. By David E. Lilienthal and Others, Harry H. Moore, Editor. Harper & Brothers, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
        - TVA - Democracy on the March. Harper & Brothers, 1944; 1 box (Box 134)
        - Miscellaneous, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Reddig, W.M., 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Reis, Alvin C, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1948; 1 box (Box 134)
    - Samuel, Viscount, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Sandburg, Carl, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Sarnoff, David, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Schlemmer, Fred C, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Schuster, M. Lincoln, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Sellar, Tim M, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Shattuck, Winfred A, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Shelton, Barrett, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Spedding, F.H., 1948; 1 box
      - Re Speeches, 1948 February 5-November; 1 box
        - Radio Executives Club New York, New York. "Atomic Energy - Where Do We Stand Today?", 1948 February 5; 1 box (Box 135)
        - Gettysburg, Pennsylvania., High School Commencement. "Youth In The Atomic Age, 1948 June 1; 1 box (Box 135)
        - University of Virginia - Commencement, 1948 June 14; 1 box (Box 135)
        - Cincinnati, Ohio, Exhibit. "Man and the Atom, 1948 November 8; 1 box (Box 135)
        - Ohio Farm Bureau "Farm People and the Atom, 1948 November 30; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Spivak, Lawrence E, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Stettinius, Edward R., Jr, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Strauss, Lewis L, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Sturdevant., W.L., 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Taft, Charles P, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Tarrant, John E, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Tennessee River Valley, 1948; 1 box
      - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1948; 1 box
        - Federal Resource Agencies, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 135)
        - Personnel Administration, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Thomas, Charles A, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Thomason, R. Ewing, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Towsley, Frank H, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Tracerlab, Inc, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Truman, Harry S, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Tully, Grace G, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., Jr, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Voorhis, Jerry, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Waller, Helen Hiett, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Waller, Theodore, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Wall Street Journal, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Wanger, Walter F, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Waymack, William W, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Webb, James, 1948; 1 box
      - Whitman, Willson (Wanda), 1948; 1 box
        - David Lilienthal. Public Servant, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 135)
        - In A Power Age., dates not examined; 1 box (Box 135)
        - Henry Holt, 1946, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Wildman, Clyde E, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Wilson, Carroll L, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Winchell, Walter, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Winship, Lawrence L, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Witte, Edwin E, 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Wood, R.B., 1948; 1 box (Box 135)
    - Chronological Files: January - December, 1948; 1 box (Box 136)
  - Subseries 3J: 1949, 1919 April 22-1949; 14 boxes
    This subseries includes correspondence to and from Lilienthal in 1949.
    - Acheson, David, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Agronsky, Martin, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Alexander, Raymond Pace, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Allen, Forrest, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Americans for Democratic Action, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Americans for Intellectual Freedom, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - American League for a Free Palestine, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - American Political Science Association, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Amrine, Michael, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Anderson, Clinton P, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Ascoli, Max, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1949; 1 box
      - Atomic Energy, 1949; 1 box (Box 137)
    - General, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Reunion Meeting, January 30-31, 1949, of the 1946 Department of State, Board of Consultants, on The International Control of Atomic Energy, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Atomic Energy Commission, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Northwest Trip Concerning Columbia Basin Project, Hanford Project, Idaho Atomic Reactor Plant, etc, 1949 May 26-October 26; 1 box
      - Atomic Energy Commission: Congressional Hearings, 1949 May 26-October 26; 1 box (Box 137)
    - File Outline, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Broadcasts, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 137)
    - Confidence, Expressions of, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 137)
    - (A - Q), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 137)
    - (N - Z), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 138)
    - Criticism, Expressions of, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 138)
    - Re Edelman, Isadore S.: Loyalty, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 138)
    - "How The Commission Spends It's Time", dates not examined; 1 box (Box 138)
    - Information: Clearance, Disclosure, Secrecy, Security, etc, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 138)
    - "Fellowship Stand", dates not examined; 1 box (Box 139)
    - General Electric Plant, Hanford, Washington - Material, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 139)
    - Travel Report Submitted to Hickenlooper, Bourke B., 1946-1949, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 139)
      Includes Travel Vouchers
    - Government Printing Office Publications, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 139)
    - Clippings [A Sample], dates not examined; 1 box (Box 140)
    - Resignation of David E. Lilienthal, Letters to: Truman, Harry S, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 140)
    - Reactions, Expressions of, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 140)
    - Clippings [A Sample], dates not examined; 1 box (Box 141)
    - Radio Transcripts, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 141)
    - Statements by McMahon, Brian; Strauss, Lewis L.; Truman, Harry S. and Webb, James, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 141)
    - Augur, Tracy B, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bacher, Robert F, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bachrach, Fabian, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Baldwin, Hanson, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Baldwin, Roger N, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Ball, William M, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Ballantine, Arthur, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Barnard, Chester I, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Barr, Stringfellow, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Baruch, Bernard M, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Beacom, Thomas H, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bergstrom, E.K., 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Berle, Adolf A., Jr, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bianculli, Mario, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Blackett, P.M.S.: Military and Political Consequences of Atomic Energy, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bliven, Bruce, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Block, Frank, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Block, Herb, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Booth, Harry R, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bowles, Chester, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bradley, Omar N, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Braunstein, Baruch, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Brockton Public Library, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Brown, Stuart Gerry, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Browne, Kenneth, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Brucker, Herbert, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bullock, William E, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Bush, Vannevar, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Byrd, Richard E, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Campbell Soup Company, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Carey, James B, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Chafee, Z., Jr, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Chase, Stuart, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Chenery, William L, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Clapp, Gordan R, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Claypool, James V, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Clifford, Clark, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Collierb, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Columbia Valley Administration, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Compton, Arthur H, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Cooke, Morris L, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Cousins, Norman, 1949; 1 box (Box 142)
    - Daniels, Jonathan, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Davies, Rev. A. Powell, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Davies, Joseph E, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Dietz, David, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Dirksen, Everett, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Drummond, Roscoe, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Dubinsky, David, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - DuBridge, L.A., 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Duffus, R,L, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Duggan, Mrs. Laurence, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Dunning, John R, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Eastman, Max, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Eccles, Marriner, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Einaudi, Mario, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Elmoke, JK., Jr, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Evans, Silliman, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Fadiman, Clifton, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Finkelstein, Louis, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Finley, S.R., 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Fisk, James B, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Forrestal, James V, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Fortune Magazine, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Franks, Sir Oliver, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Friendly, Alfred M, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Gaus, John M, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Gilden, Harold M, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Glueck, Nelson, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Goldberg, Arthur J, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Golden, William, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Gore, Albert, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Graham, Frank P, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Grose, George R, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Gunther, John, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Hall, James S, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Harper & Brothers, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Hays, Arthur Garfield, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Hill, Howard, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Hill, Lister, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Hobby, Oveta Culp, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Holifield, Chet, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - Hutchins, Robert M, 1949; 1 box
      - Invitations, 1949; 1 box (Box 143)
    - (A - C), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 144)
    - (D - Z), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 145)
    - Jackson, Gardner, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Jackson, Henry, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Johnston, Eric, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Kefauver, Estes, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - King, Judson, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - King, McKenzie: Re Markham, Violet, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Knopf, Alfred A, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Ladies Home Journal, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - La Follette, Philip F, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Lasker, Albert D, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Lawrence, David, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Lawrence, Ernest O, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Leach, W. Barton, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Lehman, Herbert H, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Leigh, W. Colston, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Levin, Robert A, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Liberal Judaism, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Lilienthal, Alfred M, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Lucas, Scott W, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Luckman, Charles, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - McAllister, Charles E, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - McCormick, Anne O'Hare, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - McGinley, Laurence J, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - McMahon, Brien, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Mann, Martin: "U.S. Lights New Atomic Pile for Peace.", 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Mansfield, Mike, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Markham, Violet, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Marshall, George C, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Merriam, Charles E, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Miscellaneous, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Morgan, Harcourt A, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Morse, Wayne, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Murray, Philip, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Murrow, Edward R, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Myler, Joseph, 1949; 1 box (Box 146)
    - Nashville Tennessean. Jubilee Edition, October 2., 1949, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - New Leader, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Newman, Montrose, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - New York Times, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Neuberger, Richard L, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Nicely, James Mount, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Oberlin College, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - O'Brian, John Lord, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Olds, Leland, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - OlMahoney, Joseph C, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Owen, Kenneth W, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Oxnam, Bishop G. Bromley, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Pageant Magazine, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Patterson, Robert P, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Patton, James G, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Percefull, Albert, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Perkins, Milo, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Perlman, Selig, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Pettes, C. Rockwell, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Phosphates, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Pike, Sumner T, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Pinchot, Cornelia Bryce, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Potter, Zenas L, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Princeton University, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Princeton University: Daily Princetonian, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Progressive, The, 1949; 1 box
      - Re Publications by David E. Lilienthal, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - New York Times Magazine. "Our Faith is Mightier Than Our Atom Bomb,", 1949 March 6; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists. "Science and the Spirit of Man,", 1949 April; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Collier's"What Good is the Atom?", 1949 June 11; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Saturday Review of Literature. "Machines With and Without Freedom,", 1949 August 6; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 147)
    - TVA - Democracy on the March. Harper & Brothers, 1947; 1 box (Box 147)
    - This I Do Believe. Harper & Brothers, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Rabi, I.I., 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Rayburn, Sam, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Reed, Philip G, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Reis, Alvin C, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1949; 1 box (Box 147)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. - Memorial Association Award: Conferred Upon David E. Lilienthal for the Publication, This I Do Believe. Harper & Brothers, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Rorty, James, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Rosenman, Samuel I, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Russell, Dean: "A Review By TVA" of The TVA Idea By Dean Russell, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Schacter, Harry W, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Schenectady, New York - Visit, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Schuster, M. Lincoln, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Sellar, Tim M, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Sessions, Robert, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Shelton, Barrett, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Shih Hu, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Smedley, Frederic C, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Smyth, Henry D, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Sparkman, John, 1949; 1 box
      - Re Speeches, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Oak Ridge, Tennessee, Community Meeting, 1949 January 6; 1 box (Box 148)
    - University of Rochester and Temple Brith Kodesh Centennial Committee. "The Spirit of Democracy,", 1949 January 16; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Lehigh University - Commencement Address and Honorary Degree Citation, 1949 February 6; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Washington State College, Pullman, Washington. "The Brighter Side of the Atom, 1949 April 20; 1 box (Box 148)
    - University of Washington., Seattle, Washington. "Atomic Energy Today", 1919 April 22; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Michigan State College - Commencement Address and Honorary Degree. "The Spirit of Democracy,", 1949 June 5; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Freedom House Award., New York, New York, 1949 October 13; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Stevenson, Adlai E, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Strauss, Lewis L, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Sturdevant, W.L., 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Sulzberger, Mrs. Arthur Hays, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Sunstrom, E. Arnold, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Sylvester, John N, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Symington, Stuart, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Taylor, William S, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1949; 2 boxes (Box 148, Box 619)
    - Foreign Interest and History, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Thomas, Charles A, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Thomason, R. Ewing, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Towsley, Frank H, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Truman, Harry S, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
      Includes Letters of Resignation from David E. Lilienthal as Chairman and Member of the Atomic Energy Commission, November 21, 1949, and December 21, 1949.
    - Urey, Harold, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Vail, Alice L, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., Jr, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Van Doren, Irita, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Volpe, Joseph, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Waller, Helen Hiett, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Waller, Theodore, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Warburg, James P, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Washington Association of Scientists, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Water, Charles T. te, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Waymack, William W, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Weeks, Edward, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Wigner, Eugene P, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Wildman, Clyde E, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Wilson, Carroll L, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Witte, Edwin E, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Wood, R.B., 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - United Nations, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Zions Herald, 1949; 1 box (Box 148)
    - Chronological Files: January - December, 1949; 1 box (Box 149)
- Series 4: Documents, 1919-1948; 2 boxes
  Series 4: Documents contains personal records of Lilienthal's academic and professional careers.
  Not arranged in a particular order.
  - 1919-1948, 1 box (Box 608)
    Include miscellaneous records, includingg passports, and records of his military service, law school exam results, appointment to and termination from his State Department position, and designation as a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
  - Appointments, commissions, degrees, and certificates, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 609, Folder Oversize folder 1, Folder Oversize folder 2)
- Series 5: Appointment Books and Lists, 1932-1948; 6 boxes
  Series 5: Appointment Books and Lists consists of Lilienthal's appointment books and daily appointment records from 1932-1948.
  The appointment books and lists are arranged in chronological order.
  - 1932-1935, 1 box (Box 151)
  - 1936-1937, 1 box (Box 152)
  - 1938-1939, 1 box (Box 153)
  - 1940-1941, 1 box (Box 154)
  - 1942-1944, 1 box (Box 155)
  - 1945-1948, 1 box (Box 156)
- Series 6: Expense Records: Tennessee Valley Authority, 1933-1946; 1 box
  Series 6: Expense Records: Tennessee Valley Authority consists of Lilienthal's financial records, predominantly expense account reports, connected to his time at the Tennessee Valley Authority.
  - 1933-1946, 1 box (Box 157)
- Series 7: Publications About or Relating to David E. Lilienthal, 1339-1949; 3 boxes
  Series 7: Publications About or Relating to David E. Lilienthal includes magazine or professional journal articles about Lilienthal, the organizations he worked for, or subject matter related to his professional career (e.g., atomic energy).
  The materials in this series are arranged in chronological order by the year in which they were published.
  - 1900-1932, 1339, 1944-1947 July, 1 box (Box 158)
  - 1947 August-1948, 1 box (Box 159)
  - 1949, 1 box (Box 160)
- Series 8: Clippings, 1886-1978; 9 boxes
  Series 8: Clippings consists of newspaper clippings about Lilienthal, the organizations he worked for, or subject matter related to his activities and professional career.
  The materials in this series are arranged in chronological order by year.
  - 1886-1933, 1 box (Box 161)
  - 1934-1940, 1 box (Box 162)
  - 1941-1943, 1 box (Box 163)
  - 1945 - 1947 February 20, 1 box (Box 164)
  - 1947 February 21 - December, 1 box (Box 165)
  - 1948-1949 May, 1 box (Box 166)
  - 1949 June-December, 1 box (Box 167)
  - 1950-1960, 1 box (Box 587)
  - 1961-1978, 1 box (Box 588)
- Series 9: Press Releases: Atomic Energy Commission, 1946 December-1949; 1 box